#
####
Futon, clothes, shoes, toothbrush...
Wasn't there something else?
Huh!?
Rin, don't go and pull disappearing acts like that!
It scares me!
Okay.
Daikichi, pick a green one.
Come on. We're going.
It'll be safer if we hold hands while we walk.
Safer for me?
Usagi
Drop
Ashita no koto wa wakaranai
明日のことはわからない
I can't tell what'll come tomorrow.
Kore tte gisei to wa chigau
これって犠牲とは違う
This is different than making a sacrifice.
Nanika ga chigau
何かが違う
Something about it is different.
Batsu geemu ja nante omowanai
罰ゲームじゃなんて思わない
And I don't think of it as some sort of forfeit.
...tte nande na no ka wakaranai
...ってなんでなのか分からない
So I just don't get why.
Chotto shakuzen to shinai kedo
ちょっと釈然としないけど
I can't quite wrap my head around it,
Kimi no sonzai ima daiji da nante mon ja nai
君の存在今大事だなんてもんじゃない
but your existence is now much more than just important to me.
Owaranai koto nante kono yo no doko ni mo nai
終わらないことなんてこの世のどこにもない
There's nothing in this world that doesn't come to an end.
Naku no wa tsurain ja nai no
泣くのは辛いんじゃないの
I don't cry because I'm hurting.
Ai no sweet drops sweet drops
愛の sweet drops sweet drops
They're the sweet, sweet drops of love!
Zutto yume mite mitai ne
ずっと夢見てみたいね
I want to go on dreaming forever, you know?
Motto yasashiku shitai ne
もっと優しくしたいね
I want to try and be more gentle, you know?
Kimi to iraretara happy
君といられたらhappy
If I can be with you, I'm happy.
Onna no ko tte tsuyoi ne
女の子って強いね
Girls are really strong, aren't they?
Dakedo tokidoki yowai ne
だけど時々弱いね
But sometimes, they can be really weak, you know?
Bokura no negai wa happy happy happy
僕らの願いは happy happy happy
Our wishes are happy, happy, happy.
Sonna hibi mo happy
そんな日々も happy
And our days will be just as happy!
Just wanna make you happy!
I want the blue one!
Since when were there so many parents with children here?
I want that one!
This?
Yeah.
Um... Okay. Looks good.
What size are you?
Don't know.
Rin, turn around.
Like this?
What am I supposed to be comparing it to?
Don't know!
Quit waving your arms around!
What else do you need?
Pajamas! Pants! Shirts! Socks!
You don't want a skirt?
You've only put trousers in here.
They don't let us wear skirts to nursery.
I see...
Nursery!?
I completely forgot!
Tomorrow's Monday, isn't it?
I'm tired, Daikichi!
It's just a little further. Be strong.
Okay...
I'm starving.
We're almost home, so...
Okay...
Are you bunking off again?
You good for nothing...
You're always bringing me stuff I don't need.
I'm going to get mad!
What's that supposed to mean? Damn idiot!
Hey!
Get your hands off me!
Let go!
Um... Excuse me...
Yes, this is the Maeda residence.
Oh, hello. I was sorry to hear about your recent loss.
Yes, please wait a moment.
Haruko-san? It's Daikichi-san.
Coming! Thanks!
Oh? Haruko?
Sorry, I never asked for your mobile number.
It's fine.
How do you go about starting nursery?
Nursery?
What!? You actually took Rin-chan home with you!?
Is it really okay?
For now.
What do you mean by "for now"?
Anyway, it's too late for me to take the day off tomorrow.
So what's the procedure to enrol her?
You can't just enrol her straight away, you know.
Can't you pull some strings?
I'm not sure I'm the right person to be asking.
You could start by asking at the city hall.
It's Sunday night.
What is it!?
No, just something on my end.
Mama, is that Rin-chan?
Are you okay?
Rin-chan!
Hey, Reina!
We're talking about something important.
Rin-chan!
There's a temporary nursery for emergencies...
A temporary nursery for emergencies?
Rin-chan!
What is it, Dai-chan?
Rin-chan! Rin-chan! Rin-chan! Rin-chan!
Ah, no, just something on my end.
I'll be done in a minute. Just wait a bit.
I can't wait!
Haruko-san, I'm taking the miso soup off the stove.
Oh! Thank you.
Hey, it sounds like you're pretty busy, so I'll call back la-
Rin-chan!
Emergency temporary nursery
Man, hardly any results...
So, suddenly I'm going to double my work commute?
Yeah. Yeah. I'm fine.
This one's pretty close, but I can't get out of work at six.
Yeah. Sure. Let's play again sometime.
Yeah. Bye bye, Reina-chan! See you!
This one looks pretty good,
but it says they'll only take kids on emergency notice for ten days.
A bath...
Wait just a little longer.
Daikichi! Daikichi!
It's morning...
Right... Sorry...
Did you sleep here?
The futon feels strangely warm.
Take this off!
Right, right...
So, about the nursery you're going to today...
Thanks for the food!
Thanks for the food...
Elbows off the table while you eat!
Right. Sorry.
The nursery you're going to is only taking you on a temporary basis, okay?
Temporary?
It means you'll go there until we can find a place to formally enrol you at.
What does "formally" mean?
It means properly.
Well, it's slightly different...
Hey, my hair's fine!
Are you okay?
I'm... fine...
I-I'm fine...
I can see it!
P-Put me down! Put me down!
What? What?
Is it embarrassing for you to have other kids see me carrying you?
Daikichi...
S-Sorry...
Please take good care of her, then.
We will. Take care.
Don't give me that look.
I won't be able to make it back while it's light,
but I'll try to be as quick as I can.
I promise.
It's a pinky promise.
If I tell a lie, I'll absolutely swallow a thousand needles.
Damn it!
My finger was cut off!
You got the song wrong.
See you. Wait for me, Rin.
I'm sorry, Rin. I never thought about how you felt.
You had no understanding of your mum's circumstances, nor of my granddad's lifespan.
You only knew the pain of being left alone.
Did you think I was going to leave you behind, as well?
I'm sure having that happen to you once...
...is more than enough to last you a lifetime.
Read this to me.
Sure!
Kawachi-san, let's grab some lunch.
Oh, I've got something here.
I got mine a little earlier.
I see. Then I'll be back in a bit.
The first day of the month and you're already in workaholic mode, huh?
It's not like that.
Get me a photo of this sample.
Will do.
Kawachi-san! There's a call for you on line four about the investors' inspection.
Coming.
This is Kawachi.
Bye bye!
Let's keep going!
Yeah.
Kawachi...
Yes? Sorry...
You're late!
Sorry, sorry...
Go and get changed.
Okay!
Rin-chan, don't break it, okay?
Bye bye!
Bye bye...
Hello? Just a moment.
Kawachi-san?
It's Miyata-san from Mitsutomo Trading.
I'll take it.
Yes? This is Kawachi.
Thank you very much.
Yes, this is Kawachi.
Yes.
I'm terribly sorry.
I'll be done at work in just a little bit.
I'm sorry.
The nursery is... so far away!
Rin! Sorry I'm late.
Welcome back.
I'm so... sorry...
Rin.
Oh, are those crisps? They look good!
Chopped vegetables!
Daikichi
I swallowed...
...a thousand needles!
Okay, I'll leave this to you.
Kawachi-san! You need to sign here!
It's not like it's actually likely,
but what if I find a girlfriend?
Daikichi! Daikichi!
Wake up!
Right... Sorry...
Kawachi. This was supposed to go out yesterday, right?
Whoa!
I'm so sorry...
This really isn't like you.
Sorry...
I've already apologised to the recipient, so...
I'm sorry. I'll call them immediately.
Let's go for a few drinks. It's been a while.
Sorry, tonight's no good.
Then how about tomorrow?
I've got something going on then, as well.
Oh, I get it. Sounds like someone's getting lucky.
Get on.
I'm fine.
Daikichi?
Hold on tight!
Daikichi! Run away from the moon!
Here goes!
Baby Bear and the Acorns
There's just no end to this!
How long can I keep living like this?
Mother and Child
Health Record
These are Rin-chan's things.
This is all that she has.
Her mother and child health record and other important documents are here, too.
Even if it's only for a short while,
raising a child is a terribly difficult job.
Surely, Rin is the one who has it the hardest.
Sorry, but I'm just going to have a little look in here.
Her mouth's still the same.
All of the relatives talk about you like you're some sort of supervillain.
But I wonder... Who's the real villain, Masako-san?
Nichiyou no hareta hirusagari
日曜の晴れた昼下がり
A sunny Sunday's early afternoon;
Kyou wa doko e yukou?
今日はどこへ行こう？
where should we go today?
Kayoinareta itsumo no michi ga
通い慣れたいつもの道が
The same old road that I'm so used to walking on...
Mabushiku kagayaite mieru
眩しく 輝いて見える
...shines with a dazzling light.
Terasu atatakai taiyou to
照らす暖かい太陽と
If I have the warm sunlight shining down on me...
Tonari ni kimi ga ireba...
隣に君がいれば
...and you by my side...
Whoa! High, high, high!
Hashagidasu kimochi ni
はしゃぎだす気持ちに
My feelings are ready to burst forth.
Utae lai lai lai!
歌え lai lai lai!
Sing out, lai lai lai!
Koe wa doko made mo
声はどこまでも
My voice reaches every corner of the earth.
Mou high high high!
もう high high high!
I'm already high, high, high!
Maiagaru kaze ni nori
舞い上がる風に乗り
Riding the whirling winds...
Utae lai lai lai!
歌え lai lai lai!
Sing out, lai lai lai!
Koe mo tobihaneru
声も飛び跳ねる
My voice swoops up and down with me.
What's wrong? Feeling sick?
So you've decided to sleep over there aft-
Huh!?
What!? D-Did I...?!
It's sweat!
Sure, sure. It's sweat.
Sweat.
I'll change the sheets, so give me a hand.
I said that it's sweat!
And I agreed!